{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Lawrence of Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["The Longest Day","Meredith Willson's The Music Man","Mutiny on the Bounty"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1962?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Jupiter","incorrectAnswers":["Saturn","Mars","Neptune"],"question":"Which planet is known for having the Great Red Spot?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1993","incorrectAnswers":["1989","1997","2001"],"question":"In which year was Groundhog Day released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Swim Across The English Channel","incorrectAnswers":["Fly Solo Across the Atlantic","Run a marathon in under 2.5 hours","Become elected as Prime Minister of the UK"],"question":"What in 1926, did Gertrude Ederle become the first woman to do?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The North Sea","incorrectAnswers":["The Mediterranean Sea","The Caribbean Sea","The Arabian Sea"],"question":"Where is Dogger Bank?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Prince","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Michael Jackson","Elton John"],"question":"What singer's \"Lovesexy\" album caused a controversy when some stores refused to stock it due to the nude cover?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Echo","incorrectAnswers":["Elton","Elbow","Enable"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter E?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cambodia ","incorrectAnswers":["Kuwait","Myanmar","Suriname"],"question":"What country was known as Kampuchea between 1975 and 1979?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The practice of breaking free from restraints","incorrectAnswers":["Schematic layouts","Survival during natural disasters","Volcanoes"],"question":"What is escapology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Chile","incorrectAnswers":["Madagascar","Jamaica","Samoa"],"question":"Santiago is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Capricorn","incorrectAnswers":["Gemini","Aries","Scorpio"],"question":"What star sign would you be if you were born on Christmas Day?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Cyndi Lauper","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Whitney Houston","Tina Turner"],"question":"Which artist released the album \"She's So Unusual\" in 1983?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Carly Simon","incorrectAnswers":["Lulu","Nancy Sinatra","Matt Monro"],"question":"Who performed the theme song to the James Bond film The Spy Who Loved Me?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Listen to them. Children of the night. What music they make.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"I'm gonna make him an offer he can't refuse.\"","\"With great power comes great responsiblity.\"","\"There's no crying in baseball!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dracula'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Black Sabbath","incorrectAnswers":["Skunk Anansie","Kasabian","Emerson, Lake & Palmer"],"question":"Which British heavy metal band released the song 'Paranoid'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Nigel Mansell","incorrectAnswers":["Damon Hill","Michael Schumacher","Jacques Villeneuve"],"question":"In 1995 Which Formula One Driver Signed For McLaren But Couldn't Fit In The Car?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Mecca","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Rome","Lhaasa"],"question":"Where is the Holy Kaaba?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pumpernickel ","incorrectAnswers":["Lumperpickel","Mumperdickel","Grumperfickel"],"question":"What is the name given to a black German rye bread?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Stuffed pasta","incorrectAnswers":["Soup pasta","Strand pasta","Ribbon pasta"],"question":"What type of pasta is ravioli?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Rasputin","incorrectAnswers":["Lenin","Stalin","Trotsky"],"question":"Who was the Russian mystic who was a favorite at the court of Nicholas II?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Brideshead Revisited","incorrectAnswers":["The Old Man and the Sea","The English Patient","Ulysses"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Charles Ryder'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blondie","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Fleetwood Mac","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which band was fronted by Debbie Harry?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Rihanna","Beyonce","Lady Gaga"],"question":"Which Female Icon Brought Out A Book Entitled \"Sex\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Cubism","incorrectAnswers":["Art Deco","Impressionism","Dadaism"],"question":"Which artistic movement employed an analytic vision based on fragmentation and multiple viewpoints?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Isaac Newton","incorrectAnswers":["Charles Darwin","Archimedes","Ernest Rutherford"],"question":"Who Was Inspired By An Apple Falling?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Friendship pins","incorrectAnswers":["Booty beads","Lucky charms","Cat tags"],"question":"Which 80's fashion accessory consisted of a saftey pin and small beads?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George R.R. Martin","incorrectAnswers":["J.R.R. Tolkien","Robert Jordan","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author is leaving audiences waiting for a sequel to his 2011 novel 'A Dance with Dragons'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"St. Louis","incorrectAnswers":["Munich","Prague","New Orleans"],"question":" Where was Budweiser first brewed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ernest Rutherford","incorrectAnswers":["Galileo Galilei","Gregor Mendel","Louis Pasteur"],"question":"Which of these people was an influential physicist who made discoveries in atomic physics?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Stovepipe","incorrectAnswers":["Tricorne","Fedora","Sombrero"],"question":"What type of hat did Abraham Lincoln famously wear?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Coatlicue","incorrectAnswers":["Tlaloc","Tezcatlipoca","Quetzalcoatl"],"question":"What was the name of the Aztec creation goddess?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Bob Dylan","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Young","Eric Clapton","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American Musician wrote the song 'Like a Rolling Stone'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Brunei","incorrectAnswers":["Cambodia","Egypt","Barbados"],"question":"Where in the world would you most expect to be served Ambuyat?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Epilepsy","incorrectAnswers":["Hemophilia","Asthma","Narcolepsy"],"question":"From what did Alexander the Great suffer?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"James Buchanan","incorrectAnswers":["Rutherford B. Hayes","Woodrow Wilson","Abraham Lincoln "],"question":"Who was the 15th president of the USA, in term during the period 1857–1861?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hey Diddle Diddle","incorrectAnswers":["Humpty Dumpty","Mary Had a Little Lamb","Baa Baa Black Sheep"],"question":"What nursery rhyme includes a cow who jumps over the moon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Mercury","incorrectAnswers":["Venus","Earth","Mars"],"question":"Which planet has the most extreme temperature variations?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hans Christian Andersen","incorrectAnswers":["Beatrix Potter","Søren Kierkegaard","Oscar Wilde"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Princess and the Pea'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Two","incorrectAnswers":["Four","Yellow","Red"],"question":"What does the word 'dos' mean in Spanish?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Wellington","incorrectAnswers":["Kingstown","Victoria","Auckland"],"question":"What is the capital city of New Zealand?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Motor Racing","incorrectAnswers":["Cycling","Tennis","Cricket"],"question":"With which sport is Sterling Moss associated?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Dry ","incorrectAnswers":["Sweet","Fruity","Light"],"question":"If A Sparkling Wine Is Labelled As 'Brut' How Will It Taste?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ouagadougou","incorrectAnswers":["Monrovia","Manila","Dushanbe"],"question":"What is the capital city of Burkina Faso?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Black Pepper ","incorrectAnswers":["Juniper","Sultanas","Cardamon"],"question":"What name is given to the unripe, ground or whole berries of Piper nigrum?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Red Sea","incorrectAnswers":["The Dead Sea","The Mediterranean Sea","The Black Sea"],"question":"In which body of water did Moses cross with the Israelites?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Rihanna","incorrectAnswers":["Drake","Nicki Minaj","Ricky Martin"],"question":"Which singer released the song 'If It's Lovin' that You Want'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Igneous Rocks","incorrectAnswers":["Sedimentary Rocks","Metamorphic Rocks","Fossils"],"question":"What type of rocks are created by the cooling and hardening of lava or magma?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Dante Alighieri","incorrectAnswers":["Giovanni Boccaccio","Agatha Christie","Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Paradiso'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bulgaria","incorrectAnswers":["Netherlands","Hungary","Albania"],"question":"In which country is the city of Sofia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"England","incorrectAnswers":["Angola","Switzerland","Bangladesh"],"question":"Which country's name is derived from a name which means 'Land of the Angles'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Transylvania","incorrectAnswers":["Moldova","Dobruja","Banat"],"question":"What is the name of the Romanian region that is known for vampire legends?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"X","incorrectAnswers":["Z","Y","Q"],"question":"In French, what letter would you use to pluralize the word 'chateau'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Hear You Scream","incorrectAnswers":["See You","Breathe","Win"],"question":"Complete this movie trailer catch line for the film Alien. 'In space no one can _____'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"The Furies","incorrectAnswers":["The Sirens","The Harpies","The Gorgons"],"question":"What name is given to the Greek female divinities who punished crimes at the request of the victims?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of Comoros is on which continent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Dayton, Ohio","incorrectAnswers":["Kitty Hawk, North Carolina","Boston, Massachusetts","Detroit, Michigan"],"question":"Where did the Wright Brothers found a firm to manufacture airplanes in 1909?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Botany","incorrectAnswers":["Zoology","Medicine","Astronomy"],"question":"Which branch of science is associated with the terms monocotyledon and dicotyledon?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tunis","incorrectAnswers":["Ankara","Algiers","Dakar"],"question":"What is the capital city of Tunisia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Cacophony","incorrectAnswers":["Cabotage","Gardyloo","Halfpace"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a harsh, discordant mixture of sounds'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cabo Verde","incorrectAnswers":["Samoa","Albania","Monaco"],"question":"Praia is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Alfred Hitchcock","incorrectAnswers":["Orson Welles","Christopher Nolan","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Who was the British-born film director who died in Los Angeles in 1980?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"One Thousand and One Nights","incorrectAnswers":["Charlotte's Web","Alice's Adventures in Wonderland","The Snow Queen"],"question":"In which book does 'Ali Baba' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Spark plugs","incorrectAnswers":["Valves","Pistons","Gaskets"],"question":"In a gas engine, what device ignites the fuel-air mixture?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A 12-year-old is taken in by a professional assassin after her family is murdered.","incorrectAnswers":["Violence and mayhem ensue after a man stumbles upon more than two million dollars.","A couple undergoes a medical procedure to have each other erased from their memories.","Two men searching for work in 1920s Mexico convince an old prospector to help them mine for gold."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Leon?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Muscat","incorrectAnswers":["Niamey","Kabul","Gitega"],"question":"What is the capital city of Oman?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cancer","incorrectAnswers":["The moon","The eyes","China"],"question":"What is Oncology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","Pink Floyd","Led Zeppelin"],"question":"The iconic album 'Abbey Road' was released by which band?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Liberia","incorrectAnswers":["Egypt","South Africa","Morocco"],"question":"William Tolbert, who was killed in a 1980 coup, was the president of which African nation?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Gianluigi Buffon","incorrectAnswers":["Leonardo da Vinci","Michelangelo","Raphael"],"question":"Which of the following is NOT a famous Renaissance artist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Quince","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Apple","Grape"],"question":"From which fruit was marmalade orginally made?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. K. Rowling","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Tolkien","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Harry Potter'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"A. A. Milne","incorrectAnswers":["Roald Dahl","Enid Blyton","Beatrix Potter"],"question":"Who created Winnie the Pooh?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1994","incorrectAnswers":["1979","1984","1989"],"question":"When was Nelson Mandela elected as South Africa’s first black president?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jaune","incorrectAnswers":["Giallo","Amarelo","Six"],"question":"What is the French word for 'yellow'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Yo Home to Bel-Air\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Bohemian Rhapsody\" by Queen","\"I'll Make a Man Out of You\" by Donny Osmond","\"In da Club\" by 50 Cent"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Now this is the story all about how / My life got flipped, turned upside down...\"?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"James Garfield","incorrectAnswers":["John F Kennedy","Abraham Lincoln","Bill Buchanan"],"question":"Which U.S. president was fatally shot in 1881?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"John Green","incorrectAnswers":["Cassandra Clare","James Fenimore Cooper","Brandon Sanderson"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Fault in Our Stars'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1983","incorrectAnswers":["1974","1993","2001"],"question":"When was laser eye surgery first used for vision correction?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Salem","incorrectAnswers":["Greensboro","Alexandria","Wilmington"],"question":"Where did the famous witch trials of New England take place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Tennis","incorrectAnswers":["Rugby Union","Volleyball","Snooker"],"question":"With which sport is Margaret Smith Court associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"A Wind ","incorrectAnswers":["A Dance","An Art Movement","A Mythical Creature"],"question":"What Is The Scirocco?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Clippers","incorrectAnswers":["Galleons","Frigates","Brigs"],"question":"Which 19th century sailing ships were known for their speed?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ghana","incorrectAnswers":["India","Australia","Egypt"],"question":"The Gold Coast gained its independence from Great Britain in 1957 and formed part of which new country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"High Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Art Nouveau","Crystal Cubism","Baroque"],"question":"The painting \"The Last Supper\" by Leonardo da Vinci is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Poult","incorrectAnswers":["A Fawn","An Infant","An Eaglet"],"question":"What is a baby turkey known as?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North Macedonia","incorrectAnswers":["Montenegro","Serbia","Bosnia and Herzegovina"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Greece?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"You had me at hello.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"I have nipples Greg. Could you milk me?\"","\"I love lamp.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Jerry Maguire'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Raiders of the Lost Ark","incorrectAnswers":["Jaws","Star Wars","E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial"],"question":"Which film contains a memorable scene where Harrison Ford retrieves a golden idol?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sir Lancelot","incorrectAnswers":["King Arthur","Merlin","Sir Gawain"],"question":"In the poem by Alfred Tennyson, who does the Lady of Shallot see out of her window, causing her to be cursed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Shan Yu","incorrectAnswers":["The Evil Queen","Ursula","Jafar"],"question":"What is the name of the villain in Mulan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pastel De Choclo","incorrectAnswers":["Moules-Frites","Pelmeni","Dal Bhaath"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Chile?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Marcel Proust","incorrectAnswers":["François-René de Chateaubriand","Umberto Eco","Alexandre Dumas"],"question":"Which author wrote 'In Search of Lost Time'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Realism","incorrectAnswers":["Mannerism","Northern Renaissance","Dutch and Flemish Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"Whistler’s Mother\" by James Abbott McNeill Whistler is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ultraviolet light","incorrectAnswers":["Radio waves","Gamma rays","Infrared"],"question":"In the electomagnetic spectrum, what comes between X-rays and visible light?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A herd","incorrectAnswers":["A pace","A barren","A gaggle"],"question":"What is the word for a group of antelopes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Fidel Castro","incorrectAnswers":["Raul Castro","Miguel Castro","Pedro Castro"],"question":"Who Established A Communist Government In Cuba in 1959?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Kidney","incorrectAnswers":["Liver","Bladder","Stomach"],"question":"Which Organ's Action Is Replaced By Artifical Dialysis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Stranger","incorrectAnswers":["One Hundred Years of Solitude","The Trial","The Quiet American"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Meursault'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Honda","incorrectAnswers":["Citroën","BMW","AC"],"question":"The Accord is a model of car made by which manufacturer?","difficulty":"medium"},